Yu-Cheng Deng

2121 Glacier Drive, Apt 15, Davis, California • Mobile: (530)302-6577 • E-mail: ycdeng@ucdavis.edu LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cheng-deng-0413/ • Personal Web: https://ycdeng0413.github.io/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A self-motivated team player who is enthusiastic about software development, computer vision, data analysis and visualization with 2+ years of solid software development experiences. Currently seeking full-time positions in the field of software development, computer vision, software test, and software QA.

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE), Overall GPA: 3.88/4.00

Sep. 2018 – Jun. 2020

National Taipei University of Technology

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. in Electrical Engineering (EE)

Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2018

SKILLS

• Language Skills:

Mandarin(native), English(proficient)

• Programming Languages:

Python, MATLAB/Simulink, C/C++, C++/CLI, R, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Software Development:Technical Skillset:

Image Processing, Computer Vision, Object-oriented Programming, Algorithm, Machine Learning Git, Bash (Shell Scripting), Open CV, SQL, .NET, Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), Windows, macOS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wintec Industries
Junior Test Engineer

Newark, CA, USA

Jun. 2019 – Aug. 2019

- Created a File Transfer Protocol (FTP) Server under Linux to which the operating machines can transfer the files
- Built the script written in C++/CLI to achieve automatic file transfer through FTP
- Constructed a user-friendly Graphical User Interface (GUI) for the production line operators to use FTP
- Implemented **Computer Vision** approach (Moving-Object Surveillance) for calculating the productivity of the Printed Circuit Board (PCB) and monitoring the production lines using **Python** and **Open CV** in **Raspberry Pi 4** integrated with **Pi camera**

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Master Research- Improved Visualization of Fiber-based Fluorescence Lifetime Imaging in a Clinical Setting

Apr. 2019 - May. 2020

- Applied algorithms and image processing to fluorescence lifetime imaging (FLIm) data visualization for classification of tumors
- Proposed a more robust algorithm for Real-time FLIm Visualization for clinical applications
- Constructed a Graphical User Interface (GUI) tool for FLIm data visualization in MATLAB for research purposes

Advisor: Prof. Laura Marcu (Department of Biomedical Engineering, UC Davis)

Coursework Project- Improvement in Reinforcement Learning for Frogger Game

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Regenerated the arcade game "Frogger game" using Python with PyGame
- Applied the reinforcement learning (Q-learning) to the Frogger game and analyze its performance
- Exploited nearest neighbor interpolation approach to improve the performance of the Q-learning for the Frogger game

Coursework Project- Human Following Robot Based on Reactive Algorithm for Safe Navigation

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Constructed a simulation environment using MATLAB/Simulink
- Utilized Simulink toolbox and MATLAB script to simulate a human following robot (Pioneer 3-DX)
- Applied biological obstacle-avoidance algorithm to the sensors and analyze the performance in the synthetic environment

Senior Project- Care System for Pressure Ulcer Patients

Jun. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Exploited the **Arduino** sensors to measure the values of the major factors (humidity, temperature, pressure, etc.) in causing ulcers
- Employed Arduino Wi-Fi to transmit the sensor data to **IoT** platforms, ThingSpeak (Web) and BLYNK (Android App)
- Used PHP with MySQL to transmit the data to the database, creating webpage for the communication between Server and Client

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

• Vice President - Taiwanese Graduate Student Association (TGSA) at the University of California, Davis

Apr. 2019 - Jun. 2020

• Chief Executive Officer - Student Union of EE Department at National Taipei University of Technology

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2016